<div type="chapter" xml:id="chapter:theology">
  <head>
    Music's Power in the Relationship between Hearing and Faith
  </head>

  <p>
    <q>How are they to believe if they have not heard?</q> St. Paul
    asked, since <cit><q>faith comes through hearing, and hearing, by the
    Word of Christ</q> (<bibl>Rom. 10:16–17</bibl>)</cit>.
    In what way, then, were hearing and faith actually linked in early
    modern Catholic understanding?
    How could the auditory art form of music affect the relationship
    between them?
  </p>
  <p>
    Catholics understood faith to be more than just assenting to the
    truth of certain propositions; in traditional terminology after
    Aquinas, that would be <term>fides informa</term> or unformed
    faith.
    Rather, fuly formed faith (<term>fides formata</term>) was a
    virtue (<term>virtus</term>) or capacity that <q>worked
    through</q> the higher virtues of hope and love.
    True faith for Catholics meant a commitment of the whole person to
    live faithfully in communion with Christ through his body, the
    Church.
  </p>
  <p>
    But how could a person acquire such faith?
    The problem was that while the truths of Catholic Christianity were
    understood to be unchanging and transcendent, a dynamic
    relationship somehow had to be formed between these objective
    truths and the experience of an individual Christian subject.
  </p>
  <p>
    Sacred music, with its powers to move the bodily affections and
    stir the intellect, would seem an apt tool for making this
    connection between objective truth and subjective experience.
    But how exactly did Catholics understand music to work in this
    dynamic of faith and hearin?
    How did music work physiologically on the body through the senses?
    And what was the task of the listener to music supposed to be, in
    order to hear music in such a way as to acquire faith and increase
    in faithful devotion and social life?
  </p>
  <p>
    This chapter situates villancicos as part of early
    modern Catholic discussions of faith and sensation.
    In the first section, it presents theological sources that can
    enhance our understanding of how music was believed to work
    spiritually to propagate faith.
    These sources reveal a certain anxiety about the role of
    individual sensory experience in faith, and uncertainty about
    whether all people really had the capacity for faith.
  </p>
  <p>
    The next section interprets villancicos that explicitly address
    themes of faith and sensation as primary sources for understanding
    the state of this question in the seventeenth-century Hispanic
    world.
    These pieces include contests of the senses and representations of
    sensory confusion (including synesthesia) and impariment.
    Two villancicos that represent comic catechism scenes between a
    friar and a deaf man who cannot understand the teaching dramatize
    the problem of making faith appeal to hearing.
  </p>
  <p>
    The last part of the chapter sketches a historically informed
    theological framework for understanding the role of music in
    villancicos, drawing on the Neoplatonic writings of Fray Luis de
    Granada and Athanasius Kircher.
    Within this framework, we may propose three primary theological
    functions of villancicos—mnemonic, contemplative, and affective.
    Each function calls for a different type of listening practice for
    one who would seek to hear music as a way of growing in faith.
  </p>

  <div type="section"
       xml:id="ch:theology::sec:challenge_faith_hearing">
    <q rend="block">
      <cit>
	<p>
	  Since, therefore, faith is conceived by means of hearing, it is
	  apparent, how necessary for achieving eternal life are the works
	  of the legitimate teachers and ministers of the faith. [...]
	</p>
	<p>
	  Those who are called to this ministry should understand that
	  in passing along the mysteries of faith and the precepts of
	  life, <em>they must accomodate the teaching to the sense of
	  hearing and intelligence</em>, so that by these [mysteries and
	  precepts], <em>those who possess a well-trained sense</em>
	  should be filled up by spiritual food.
	</p>
	<bibl>
	  Catechism of the Council of Trent, 1614 edition
	</bibl>
	<!-- TODO add original Latin -->
      </cit>
    </q>
    <p>
      The quotations at the beginning of this and the next two
      sections provide distinct perspectives on the fundamental
      question of how hearing was involved in acquiring faith.
      <!-- TODO continue diss p. 53 -->
    </p>
  </div>
    
  
</div>
